so I wanted to film a quick video on
Sumo de form because so many people
screw this up and I haven't seen many
good tutorials on this um here's what
you'll see most people do they'll kind
of get a wide stance they'll line up
with the bar away from their shins and
then they'll go like this and this is
just kind of like a wide like a squat
like a mixture between a Deft and a
squat with wide stance and they'll go
like this
that that is not good form you will
never get that strong this way so see
where I am right now see how far away
from the bar I am I'm this far away my
shins are that far away from the bar
your shins should be touching the bar
with the Sumo so I'm going to line up my
shins are touching the bar I'm going to
make sure my feet are flared out I'm
taking a wide stance so I need you know
at least a 45° foot flare
The Wider you go the more you will
externally rotate the hips and turn the
feet out okay here's the next thing as I
sit down I'm going to spread my knees
out I will actually feel my upper glutes
pushing my hips
out um and and that's what you see when
you see people at the bottom their knees
are like this and they need to be out
like this so what what it looks like is
this I come way up see how wide my
stance is and come down like this so my
hips are high but I keep my chest up
then my arms are straight down you'll
see a lot of people with their arms out
here or too narrow you want your arms
straight down because this is the
shortest path out here and out here is
not ideal straight down knees are out
bar is touching my shins chest is up my
hips are high but my chest is still up
and then from here deep
breath squeeze my glutes skin my body on
the way down bar is touching my
shins just like that so again from the
side
view I am going to be you know knees out
chest up I'm not down like this and I'm
not like this so you'll see this nice
comfortable position where it's knees
hips shoulders so you'll see shoulders
here hips here knees here for most
people all right so one more
demonstration I get a wide
stance feet are turned out I'm using the
lines on the bar the little
rings to make sure I'm
symmetrical I drop down arms straight
down uh knees are pushed out chest up
squeeze my glutes at lock out sit
back keep my knees out on the way down
too bar skims the body hope you enjoy
the video